Jacobus on them.
Okay, are we are we ready?
We're good. All right, good morning
church. Hallelujah.
Is someone excited to be in [singing]
the house of God [music] again this
morning?
this morning.
>> [music]
>> You are welcome to our workers, stewards
of discipleship service
today.
I just like to share something with you
very quickly.
Well,
I don't have a particular title for
this, but I
just put it in a in a sentence.
Don't allow your service to be a
cover-up or a camouflage for your being
rooted in Christ.
There is a very, very good chance that
serving God, serving in a unit, serving
in a department can become a cover-up
for
true discipleship.
A life of service
without fellowship after a while becomes
effective.
It's
important that before we serve
before we start to serve God with our
time, with our effort, there is while
that that is great, every believer
should serve.
But the first and the most important
thing that every believer should start
with
is their being rooted in a certain
lifestyle.
And one of that lifestyle is a life of
the word.
All right?
That's what Jesus told
in John chapter 8 and verse 31. John
chapter 8 and verse 31, can we have it
on the screen?
It says, "Then said he to the Jews that
believed on him and this is what Jesus
said to them."
He said, "Now that you believe, if you
continue in my word he said, "then are
you my disciples indeed. If you continue
in my word." Can I have the old King
James? If you continue in my word, then
are you my disciples indeed. He didn't
say, "Well, you need to start serving
God now. You need to start doing this.
You need to start doing that." The first
instruction that he gave to those who
believed in him was for them to
establish a lifestyle of God's word. If
you go again to Acts chapter 2 and verse
42, Acts chapter 2 and if you read from
verse 40, you would see 3,000 souls that
that God saved. Acts chapter 2 and verse
40.
Acts chapter 2 and verse 40.
All right. And with many other words,
did he testify and exhort, saying, "Save
yourselves from this untoward
generation."
Then they gladly received his word. They
that gladly received his word were
baptized, and the same day there were
added onto them about 3,000 souls. And
then look at the next thing that they
began to do. Verse 43. 42. 42. And then
they continued steadfastly in the
apostles' doctrine. While I'm sure some
people would have joined the ushering
department, some people would have
joined the music ministry, some others
would have joined, you know, one
department or the other serving. But he
said, "That's not the first thing to
establish. The first thing to establish
is this life of a believer. The life of
Look at what he said. And they continued
steadfastly in the apostles' doctrine.
That's the word. And fellowship.
They They are friends became all the
believers. And in breaking of bread, and
in prayers.
Are you with me this morning? So, you
can see that before service, there's a
pattern that must be established, which
is a life of the word. In Luke chapter
10 and verse 40,
in Luke chapter 10 verse 40, Jesus gave
about the parable about these two ladies
that Jesus was lodging in their house.
And he said, "But Martha was cumbered
about much serving. Can you see serving
there? And there's nothing wrong with
serving.
Somebody needs to cook the meal.
Hallelujah. Because come on, hallelujah.
After the service, people will still
need to eat. I can imagine I'm having
Jesus our Lord Jesus in my house. I'm
going to be very, very concerned about
where he's going to sleep, what the
guests are going to eat and all that.
But look at that. And she approached him
and said, "Lord, you do not care that my
sister has left me to serve a Lord.
Therefore, tell her
tell her to help me." And then Jesus
answered and said, "Martha, Martha, you
are worried and troubled about many
things.
But one thing." Somebody say one thing.
>> One thing.
>> I can't hear you, somebody.
>> He didn't say the other is not
necessary, but the the challenge with
Martha and Mary was their priority.
And Jesus was letting us know that one
should come before the other one.
This one thing is needful, and Mary has
chosen that good part which will not be
taken away from her. So, Jesus
established here our Lord Jesus
established here that before you go to
service, establish your fellowship with
God. Establish your fellowship with the
word. Establish your your
certain things the Bible says you and I
should be established in. Guess what?
One of the things that happens when a
believer is not first and foremost
established in this lifestyle, and then
they go on to start serving is they they
they they get offended. Have you seen
offended workers?
Have you seen offended workers? This
this this older lady became offended at
her sister that she even charged at
Jesus.
Tell her to come join me in the kitchen.
How can she sit down be listening and
I'm all by myself alone? You know, it's
like you're trying to lift weights and
you have not eaten.
Are you with me somebody? You know how
tired how how hard that's going to be?
Trying to lift weights having not eaten.
And before you're trying to lift some
weights and you start to serve others,
feed.
Sit down, eat. You will still need to
worship. You still need to serve God
with your lives, serve God with your
time, serve God with what you've got.
But it doesn't the service is first is
is an offshoot of the time of fellowship
with God. Are you with me somebody?
Come on, are you here this morning?
So because it's very easy for us as
pastors, somebody just gets saved, we've
not established them in a life of of the
word, a life of faith. We just hurry
them into service.
There is nothing wrong if they have been
established in this lifestyle and they
are serving at the same time. They
should serve.
But there's everything wrong when we are
trying to establish them in service
without having first established their
lifestyle of feeding on the word of God,
on being established in grace, being
established in the faith, being
established in fellowship first and
foremost. Are you with me somebody?
Come on, are you with me somebody?
It is very is also very easy for service
to become a camouflage.
A worker can think that he's fine, he's
not feeding, he's not in fellowship,
he's just serving and serving and
serving. That now becomes a camouflage
thinking that they are fine. They are
not fine.
I remember one of our
one of our members, you know, somebody
one of our members who got married and
then they
the wife
joined us in church and then she became
very steadfast in serving in the
children's church.
So, she would go weeks. It was when we
just started children's church. She
would go weeks
and months
not being in the service because she
needs to go serve the children.
She was serving and serving and serving,
but she wasn't being fed herself. You
know, there is what you are doing, but
there's also what you are receiving. The
first is to sit down.
Let me tell your neighbor say, "Sit down
first."
Come on, tell your neighbor say, "Sit
down first."
Before you start serving, before you
start going about things, ensure that
you sit down, you are well fed.
You are well fed. You know, there's this
analogy in the airplane that if there's
an emergency, God forbid, in an airplane
is that when the oxygen mask drops, even
if your kids are beside you
he said, "You have to lower the oxygen
mask and put it over your face first."
Because it's when you are surviving or
you can survive that you have the
ability to be able to help your kids.
Are you with me, somebody?
Sit down first. That's one of the things
that we're trying to establish by the
grace of God for for workers to sit down
first.
Develop a life of prayer.
Develop a life of worship. So, develop a
life of um feeding on God's word,
studying God's word, meditating on the
word of God, practicing the word of God,
fellowshipping with other believers. You
know,
a life of love, being rooted in the love
of Christ, and all rooted in the love of
God and all that. Then it's easy to
serve.
It's easy to be a blessing. God said to
Abraham, "Abraham, I will bless you, and
you will be a blessing."
So, that's the pattern. I will bless
you, and you will be a blessing. Be
blessed first. Feed first. And then you
can be a blessing to others. Glory to
God, somebody.
Come on, glory to Jesus, somebody. I'll
give you a list of if if you list a list
of things that the Bible says we should
be established in. Can I have Ephesians
chapter 3 and verse
verse 16?
Ephesians 3 and verse 16.
Ephesians 3 verse 16. We can read from
verse 15. Paul was talking to the
Ephesians church and this is what he
said, "From whom the whole family in
heaven and earth is named."
All right, let's go from verse 14. So,
you see it's a prayer. It said, "For
this reason I bow my knees to the father
of our Lord Jesus Christ
from whom the whole family in heaven and
earth is named."
That he would grant you according to the
riches of his glory to be strengthened
with might through his spirit in the
inner man. Look at that. That Christ may
dwell in your hearts by faith, that you
being what?
And
grounded in what?
Love. And when the Bible says that you
may be able to comprehend with all the
saints
that I wouldn't have the time to read
all. But what the Bible is saying a
believer must be rooted and grounded in
first and foremost is the knowledge of
the love of God for them.
When you are rooted in the fact that God
loves you no matter what.
God no matter the challenge because
that's one of the first things the enemy
wants to overthrow.
That God doesn't love you, that's why
you're going through what you're going
through. That God is no longer around
because you are not hearing his voice or
you are not seeing anything that looks
as if you know Bible says when you even
when you walk through the valley of the
shadow of death, they said I will fear
no evil says for thou art with me.
Are you with me, somebody? He said,
"When you walk through the fire See,
what the fire wants to make you think of
is that God is no longer with you.
God doesn't love you anymore." So, Bible
says a believer must be established in
the fact of God's love for them.
before you can start loving God back.
First John chapter 4 verse 19 says, "We
love him because he first what?"
So, before you can start to show your
love for him, you have to be established
in his love for you.
Look at another thing the Bible says for
us to be established in.
Colossians chapter 2 and verse 7.
Colossians chapter 2 and verse 7. Look
at this.
He said, "Can we go from verse 6?"
As you therefore received Christ Jesus
the Lord, so walk in him.
Rooted. Somebody say rooted.
Come on. Somebody say rooted. He says,
"Rooted in him and built up and
established in the faith."
Established in the faith. If you're
going to be rooted in something, it
means you are growing. Are you Are you
with me, somebody?
You are rooted in him. You are
established in the faith. So, Bible says
for us to be rooted in the love of God,
for us to be established in the faith.
Let's look at something else. Galatians
chapter 2 and so
Acts chapter 16 and verse 5. Look at
another word where the Bible where Paul
was telling the church that they be
rooted in their faith. Look at this.
Acts chapter
All right. So, then the churches were
strengthened in the faith. Can I have
the old King James? The old King James
says they were established in the faith.
So, God wants you and I to be
established in the faith. What else does
the Bible want us to be established in?
Hebrews chapter 13 and verse 9.
Hebrews chapter 13 and verse 9. It says
it's a good thing that you have be
established and not be carried away with
divers and strange doctrines because
there will be divers
and strange doctrines. For it is good
that the heart be established with what?
Come on. The heart be established with
what?
He said that it's good that the heart be
established with grace.
And there is no way your heart is going
to be established in grace
if you are not constantly exposed to the
word of grace.
Acts 20, I believe verse 32, I commend
you to God
and to the word of his grace.
20:32
Acts 20:32
I commend you to God
and the word of his grace.
All right, which is able to what?
Come on, which is able to what?
So, you won't be built up if you are not
constantly exposed to the word of his
grace. You know, one thing one other
thing the Bible calls the the word the
the the word of God, it calls it the
word of faith. Romans 10:8
Romans 10:8
All right, but what sayeth the word is
nigh thee, even in thy mouth and in thy
That is the word of the word of faith.
So, if you're going to be established in
faith, ladies and gentlemen, what should
be your natural communion?
The word.
And there are four things we do with the
word.
Five things. We hear the word.
Are you with me, somebody?
We read the word.
We study the word.
Are you with me, somebody?
You meditate on the word.
Come on, are you with me, somebody? Uh
that makes it six. We practice the word.
Come on, and number six you speak the
word. I can give you scriptures for all
of them.
You hear the word. Romans 10:17
Faith comes by hearing and hearing by
the word of God. You read the word. Give
yourselves to these things. All right.
Uh I'll get you that scripture. You
What's the third one? You study the
word. Second Timothy 2:15. Study uh to
show thyself approved unto God a workman
that needs not be ashamed rightly
dividing the word of truth. You meditate
on the word many scriptures for that
one. Joshua 1:8.
Um this book of the law shall not depart
out of your mouth, but only you shall
meditate day and night. You what else?
You practice the word. Hebrews 5
and verse 14.
And um John James 1 and verse 22 to 25.
And then what else? Whoso looks into the
perfect law of liberty and and continues
therein and does not He said
this man will be blessed in all what he
does. You speak the word. And this book
of the law shall not depart out of your
mouth. The word of faith which we
Hallelujah somebody. Glory to God. So
that's the pattern that we want to
operate in by the grace of God that all
our workers are first and foremost
established. One of the problems with
having workers who are not growing
because if you don't have this lifestyle
you won't be growing. One of the
problems they become a problem to
themselves unto the unto the church.
1 Corinthians 3 and verse 1.
This is what they become a problem.
They are in the church, but they are not
growing. I could not speak unto you as
unto spiritual but as unto carnal even
as unto babes in Christ. Hebrews 5 and
verse 12. It says for when you ought to
have been teachers it says you have need
that somebody teach you again which be
the first principles of the oracles of
God and have become such as have need of
milk and not of strong meat.
Glory to God. Father we ask in the name
of Jesus that you will help us
to be established in the life of the
word,
a life of prayer,
a life of faith
that we'll be established in grace
so that we may bring forth fruit, so
that we can grow up into you in all
things,
so that our inheritance in you can be
put into our hands and so that we can be
worthy representatives and ambassadors
of the kingdom. We give you praise,
Father, in Jesus mighty name.
Amen. Hallelujah. [music] Somebody put
your hands together. Celebrate Jesus.
If you are celebrating Jesus, you can do
it better than that.
Okay, somebody saying, "Why is Pastor
talking like this today?"
I've been Is there somebody wondering?
Oh, I'm not done.
I have announcements so that we can Can
I have
All right. We're trying to speak to a
global audience now, all right?
Let's start thinking like that, like
one, and start acting like one. I
realize that my English my
I'm becoming I'm starting to talk like
our people.
And God forbid.
So, sometimes
choir, you guys need to hear yourselves
and watch yourselves.
You wouldn't know what you're doing
until you start rewatching and you start
hearing yourselves.
I've been hearing myself lately. I don't
like what I'm hearing.
Um so, I'm trying to work on my
Is it Is it diction or what they call
it?
Whatever. So, I want to be able to talk
in a way that Canadians, Americans, and
guess what?
Every one of you here, you have you have
a global calling.
I don't know what the gifts of God
within you is. We stopped streaming.
Uh I said we should stop now.
I said we should stop when we when I got
to the stage.
I did not say it.
I didn't say it.